Guide to the Michael Lerner Collection on MAD Magazine research, 1951-2005 SPEC.CGA.MLM
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
Michael Lerner Collection on Mad Magazine Research
1951-2005
SPEC.CGA.MLM
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
12.0 Cubic feet (34 boxes)
This collection contains articles and clipping, other types of publications, recordings of television and radio programs that reference some aspect of Mad Magazine, whether its history, artists, founder, subject matter, or contribution to popular culture. The collection was assembled by Michael Lerner, an enthusiast of Mad magazine and popular culture collector.
The collection consists of 20 pamphlet file boxes, 4 record cartons, 5 flat file boxes, and 4 Hollinger boxes.
Scope and Contents
The Michael Lerner Collection on MAD Magazine Research, 1951 to 2005, contains articles, television, and radio programs that reference some aspect of Mad Magazine, whether its history, artists, founder, subject matter, or contribution to popular culture. The collection was assembled by Michael Lerner an enthusiast of Mad magazine and popular culture collector.
The collection consists of two series, Audiovisual and Articles. The Audiovisual Series contains segments of television news programs that feature content on Mad Magazine or television programs in which a reference is made to Mad. Also included is the Mad Show Skits that appeared on the Ed Sullivan program in 1966, in addition to several taped episodes of the comedy sketch program Mad TV that aired on FOX in the 1990s. Also in the Audiovisual Series are segements of radion programs in which Mad magazine artists were interviewed or announced the 1992 death of Mad founder William M. Gaines. The material in the Audiovisual Series was recorded by the collection's creator from broadcast programs for his personal research. The material is all magnetic media and is in fair condition. It may need to be evaluted by BICLM for durabilty before being played on a VHS or audiocassette player.
The series Articles in divided into two subseries based on format of the materials and contains articles about Mad magazine or references to Mad magazine, either its artists, creator, or characters (for example many articles show the character Alfred E. Neuman or his catch phrase "What, me worry?"). Information on the articles including title of publication, article title, date, and brief description of subject matter was gathered from a spreadsheet originally compiled by the collection's creator and later provided to BICLM staff. The subseries, Articles in Publications contains intact magazines with the title the publication, followed by the article title in quotations. If known, the page number of the article and a brief description of the subject matter will appear in a scope note for the item. The other subseries, Article Clippings are loose clippings of articles and when possible the publication title, article title, and date have been listed.
Arrangement of Materials
This collection is arranged in 2 series:
Series 1: Audiovisual, 1966-1998 Series 2: Articles, 1951-2005 Subseries 1: Articles in Publications, 1951-2000 Subseries 2: Article Clippings, 1967-2005
Acquisitions Information
CGA.MLM.2016: Michael Lerner, 2016
Access to Materials
Materials in this collection are available for use, but may be used in the Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum reading room only. Audiovisual materials may need a use copy produced before access is allowed. Contact the Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum reading room for more information.
Biographical Note
Michael Lerner is a collector of Mad magazine memorabilia materials living in Shaker Heights, OH.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The collection includes VHS video cassette tapes and audio cassette tapes and is in fair condition. The audiovisual material requires a television and VHS player and audiocassette taper player to access the material. Please note the audiovisual material in in fair condition and will need to be evaluted by a BICLM staff member prior to use.
Mad (New York, N.Y.: 1958).; Comic books, strips, etc
- Audiovisual, Bulk, 1987-1993; 1966-1998
  - 60 Minutes: MAD Magazine, September 20, 1987 (Box MLM 1, Tape 1)
  - Fred Astaire, Undated (Box MLM 1, Tape 2)
  - Australian TV Show; The Simpsons MAD cameo; Ed Sullivan MAD Show, Undated (Box MLM 1, Tape 3)
  - BOB with Sergio Aragones, January 29, 1993 (Box MLM 1, Tape 4)
  - CNBC Steals and Deals: MAD Art Auction, January 12, 1993 (Box MLM 1, Tape 5)
  - CNBC: MAD Magazine- The Real Story; Later with Bob Costas: Bill Gaines Interview, April 1, 1991 (Box MLM 1, Tape 6)
  - CNN/ Headline News: Mort Drucker Segment (2 versions); VH-1: Don Martin Cartoon Promos; David Letterman Show: Alfred E. Newman (in photo);CNN/Headline News: MAD's Dick DeBartolo Hard Yocks book; CNBC: MAD; CNN/Headline News: Sotheby's Auction; H. Kurtzman, Dick DeBartolo, July 21, 1990; August, 1990; September 26, 1990; January 6, 1992; January 18, 1992; January 8, 1992; December 15, 1993; December 15, 1994 (Box MLM 1, Tape 7)
  - Comic Book Confidential: A Film by Ron Mann (Canadian 1988), Records on Cinema, July 5, 1990 (Box MLM 1, Tape 8)
  - Comic Book Confidential, Undated (Box MLM 1, Tape 9)
  - Stan Lee Invites You to Visit the Comic Book Greats: Sergio Aragones, Undated (Box MLM 1, Tape 10)
  - Stan Lee Invites You to Visit the Comic Book Greats: Kurtzman and Davis, Undated (Box MLM 1, Tape 11)
  - Conan O'Brian: Don Martin Appearance, December 9, 1993 (Box MLM 1, Tape 12)
  - The Ed Sullivan Show: The MAD Show Skits, January 23, 1966 (Box MLM 1, Tape 13)
  - Entertainment Tonight: MAD Book; Late Night: Paul McCartney, November 6-7, 1991 (Box MLM 1, Tape 14)
  - Hard Copy: MAD Magazine, Show No. 114, February 22, 1990 (Box MLM 1, Tape 15)
  - Good Morning America: MAD Magazine Segement (backup copy); Money Report: Collecting Comics, December 7, 1991; December 9, 1991 (Box MLM 1, Tape 16)
  - William Gaines Obituary: NBC, CBS, CNN, ABC, Entertainment Tonight; Entertainment Tonight: MAD; The MAD Magazine TV Special, June 3, 1992; January 27, 1992; 1970s (Box MLM 1, Tape 17)
  - William Gaines Obituary: ABC, CNBC; MAd Art Auction; Extra: MAD TV, June 3, 1992; February 16, 1993; October 13, 1993 (Box MLM 1, Tape 18)
  - Bill Gaines Memorial Service, June 5, 1992 (Box MLM 2, Tape 1)
  - Howard Stern Stuff, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 2)
  - Patridge Family Reunion; Arsenio Hall Show, 1993 (Box MLM 2, Tape 3)
  - NBC Sunday Today: MAD Magazine; Later with Bob Costas; Good Morning America: Bill Gaines Interview, Ocotber 20, 1990; April 1, 1991; November 7, 1991 (Box MLM 2, Tape 4)
  - Kids Are People, February 10, 1979 (Box MLM 2, Tape 5)
  - PM Magazine: Behind the Scenes of MAD Magazine, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 6)
  - MAD Video Al Feldstein, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 7)
  - Movies and TV Shows featuring MAD, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 8)
  - Personal FX Collectors Show Starring "MAD Mike", April 20, 1995 (Box MLM 2, Tape 9)
  - Various MAD Clips including Christie's Auction Outtakes, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 10)
  - The History of Comics, Volume 2, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 11)
  - "Sundae in New York; Clay Animation by Jimmy Picker, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 12)
  - MAD, MAD World, April 9, 1997 (Box MLM 2, Tape 13)
  - NRHA Today: MAD Magazine Funny Car Segment, January 25, 1998 (Box MLM 2, Tape 14)
  - MAD Exhibit OSU, October 6, 1991 (Box MLM 2, Tape 15)
  - Up the Academy, 1980 (Box MLM 2, Tape 16)
  - MAD Cartoon, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 17)
  - Steals and Deals: D. DeBartolo at the Toy Fair; Night of Living Duck; All Things Considered: M. Reidelbach radio interview, February 23, 1992; Undated; November 15, 1994 (Box MLM 2, Tape 18)
  - The Simpsons: MAD Magazine featured, December 27, 1992 (Box MLM 2, Tape 20)
  - The Comic Book Vid Scene: Vol. 1 Horrow Comics in the 50's, Undated (Box MLM 2, Tape 19)
  - The Simpsons: Marge Goes to Jail, August 5, 1993 (Box MLM 2, Tape 21)
  - The Simpsons: Pool Episode with MAD Cameo, 01/15/1995 (Box MLM 2, Tape 22)
  - The Simpsons, 04/28/1996 (Box MLM 2, Tape 23)
  - The Simpsons: Visit to the MAD Office, 09/21/1997 (Box MLM 3, Tape 1)
  - MAD TV Pilot, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 2)
  - MAD TV Tape #1, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 3)
  - MAD TV Tape #2, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 4)
  - MAD TV Tape #3, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 5)
  - MAD TV Tape #4, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 6)
  - MAD TV Tape #5, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 7)
  - MAD TV Tape #6, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 8)
  - MAD TV Tape #7, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 9)
  - MAD TV Tape #8, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 10)
  - MAD TV Tape #9, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 11)
  - MAD TV Tape #10, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 12)
  - MAD TV, 04/20/1995 (Box MLM 3, Tape 14)
  - MAD TV: MAD Goes to the Movies, 03/10/1996 (Box MLM 3, Tape 13)
  - MAD TV: Final Air Copy Show 110, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 15)
  - The Best of MAD TV, 01/07/1996 (Box MLM 3, Tape 16)
  - MAD TV Special and Rare Munsters, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 17)
  - Totally MAD B-roll (Betacam), Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 18)
  - Dick DeBartolo, 12/07/1994 (Box MLM 3, Tape 20)
  - Howard Stern Show: Nick Meslin and Ficcara Visit, 08/29/1995 (Box MLM 3, Tape 19)
  - Musically MAD Bernie Green, Undated (Box MLM 3, Tape 21)
  - MAD Disco, 1980 (Box MLM 3, Tape 22)
  - WMMS (Cleveland, OH)- Afternoon News Segement, William Gaines Obit, 06/03/1992 (Box MLM 3, Tape 23)
- Articles, 1951-2005
  - Article Clippings, 1967-2005
    - New York Times, "William M. Gaines Is Dead at 70; Was Publisher of MAD Magazine", June 4, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - New York Times, "William M. Gaines Tribute", June 10, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Comic Buyer's Guide, "William M. Gaines Tribute", June 26, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "W.M. Gaines, eccentric boss of MAD magazine", June 4, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "We mourn 7 heroes' Explosion of Challenger shocks the nation", January 29, 1986 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Cartoonist for MAD still poking fun", September 29, 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Free Times, "Cleveland's Immortal Hero", September 2-8, 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Shrugging off grip of Old Man Winter", February 21, 1993 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, Charles Schulz retirement comic, February 13, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Collectors' Corner", April 28, 1995 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Alfred E. Neuman has turned Pitchman", April 16, 2002 (Box MLM 28)
    - USA Today, August 5, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - USA Today, "'MAD' Publisher Gaines leaves madcap legacy", June 4, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - USA Today, "Artist goes away 'MAD'", November 10, 1987 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "It was a MAD plot, but hardly what the FBI thought", October 5, 2002 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Alfred E. Neuman's roots in Ohio politics", April 19, 2002 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "MAD editors are just mad about praise", July 2, 2005 (Box MLM 28)
    - Columbus Dispatch, "Still MAD after all these years", November 25, 1995 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Don Martin, cartoonist for MAD magazine", January 9, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Beacon Journal, "Don Martin, MAD magazine cartoonist", January 8, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - New York Times, "Don Martin, 'MAD's Maddest Artist,' Is Dead at 68", January 8, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, Charles Schulz retirement comic, January 3, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Parody fans can go 'Totally MAD' with CD-ROM retrospective", August 23, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "'MAD TV' members love beinglife of the parody", October 14, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Kelly Freas, illustrator MAD Magazine and NASA", January 4, 2005 (Box MLM 28)
    - Quality Paperback Book Club, "MAD about the Sixties", Undated (Box MLM 28)
    - USA Today, "Before you invest, investigate", September 19, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Art News, Altoids Spy vs. Spy ad, Summer 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - TV Guide, "Cheers and Jeers", July 8, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - The Journal of Madness, January 2, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - TV Guide, "Unimpeachably MAD!", September 25, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - CBG Comics Price Guide, January 6, 1989 (Box MLM 28)
    - Opera News, "A mad look at Trovatore", February 18, 1967 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cartoonist Profiles, Letter, November 18, 1991 (Box MLM 28)
    - Miami Herald, "Get the Point"; "Fighting MAD", May 20, 1990 (Box MLM 28)
    - Comic Shop News 565, April 22, 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - Comic Shop News 580, "Upcoming comics - MAD in October", August 5, 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - Daily News, "Worried, MAD returning to roots", April 2, 1997 (Box MLM 28)
    - New York Observer, "Happy Midlife, Dave! What, You Worry?", April, 14, 1997 (Box MLM 28)
    - Wine Spectator, "MAD's Gaines...", June 1-15, 1981 (Box MLM 28)
    - Just Kids Nostalgia, "163 MAD Magazine Button-Alfred E. Neauman", Undated (Box MLM 28)
    - Gemstone Publishing, "Tales Calculatedd to Drive you MAD", Spring/Summer 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - TV Guide, November 9, 1996 (Box MLM 28)
    - USA Today, "Method to 'MAD TV' is edgy parody", March 12, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - USA Today, "Sergio Aragones, the magazine's marginalized artist", August 13, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - Humor in a Jugular Vein, 1991 (Box MLM 28)
    - Humor in a Jugular Vein, 1991 (Box MLM 28)
    - Humor in a Jugular Vein, 1991 (Box MLM 28)
    - Greater Lafayette Museum of Art, Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Box MLM 28)
    - Sonoma County Realtors Grapevine, "Meet Mark J. Cohen", March 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Press Democrat, "The Face Behind the Laugh", May 8, 1988 (Box MLM 28)
    - June 10, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Greenberg, "What, me SAD?", 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Jim Scancarelli, Gasoline Alley, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Grapevine, "It's a MAD, MAD Magazine World", Winter 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Mark J. Cohen's Catalog #2, "Dave Berg and Paul Peter Porges from MAD", Undated (Box MLM 28)
    - Entertainment Weekly, December 7, 2001 (Box MLM 28)
    - Entertainment Weekly, "In Memoriam 2000" (Box MLM 28)
    - Sun-Sentinel, "Drawn into History", March 8, 1996 (Box MLM 28)
    - TV Guide, "Happy Tanksgiving! now go stuff yourself", November 20-21, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - TV Guide, "Livin' La Vida MAD!", November 27, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - Miami Herald, "Irreverent MAD magazine cartoonist Don Martin"", January 8, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Miami Herald, "Don Martin, legendary cartoonist, dies", January 7, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Yahoo! News, "'MAD' Magazine Cartoonist Dies", January 7, 2000 (Box MLM 28)
    - Press Democrat, "SR Agent for cartoonists Cohen, 57, dies of cancer", December 21, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - TV Guide, "100 episodes... and still tasteless!", November 6-7, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - TV Guide, "You won't believe where we found the truth...", November 13-14, 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - USA Today, "After 48 ad-free years, 'MAD' sells out", February 13, 2001 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, March 22, 2001 (Box MLM 28)
    - Kelly Freas, 82, death, January 14, 2005 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "Phil Interlandi, veteran free-lance magazine cartoonist", May 24, 2002 (Box MLM 28)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, "MAD magazine's artist Dave Berg dies of cancer", May 24, 2002 (Box MLM 28)
    - Yahoo! News, "Dave Berg Dies of Cancer at Age 81", May 24, 2002 (Box MLM 28)
    - MAD Bibliography and Related Articles, January 13, 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - Rhino Direct, "MAD Grooves", Winter 1996 (Box MLM 28)
    - Entertainment Weekly - Studio Store, "MAD TEE", Spring 1996 (Box MLM 28)
    - What on Earth, Alfred E. For President Tee; It's a MAD MAD MAD MAD World, Autumn 1992 (Box MLM 28)
    - The Mind's Eye, "MAD About the Sixties", Summer 1997 (Box MLM 28)
    - Rhino Direct, MAD T-Shirt, Undated (Box MLM 28)
    - Mark J. Cohen Catalog of Original Cartoon Art, Undated (Box MLM 28)
    - Mark J. Cohen Catalog of Original Cartoon Art Vol. 2, Undated (Box MLM 28)
    - Mark J. Cohen Catalog of Original Cartoon Art Vol. 3, Undated (Box MLM 28)
    - Gemstone Publishing, Russ Cochran's Comic Art Auction #49, October 9, 1996 (Box MLM 28)
    - Humor in the Jugular Vein, 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - Humor in the Jugular Vein, 1994 (Box MLM 28)
    - Letter to Michael Lerner from MAD, December, ca. 1999 (Box MLM 28)
    - Ohio State University, "The Festival of Cartoon Art", 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - Ohio State University, "The Genius of Winsor McCay", 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - Ohio State University, ""Humor in a Jugular Vein", 1998 (Box MLM 28)
    - MAD TV Episode Guide, 1995-1996 (Box MLM 28)
    - Santa Rosa, California, Don't get MAD, get autographs, February 21, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Santa Rosa, California, Don't get MAD, get autographs, February 21, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Humor in a Jugular Vein, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Humor in a Jugular Vein, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - The Muse, Humor in a Jugular Vein, January/February/March 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Sonoma County Business Education Roundtable, How to Get a Job and Keep It, 1993 (Box MLM 29)
    - Piraro, Bizarro, 1998 (Box MLM 29)
    - Museum, Undated (Box MLM 29)
    - SF museum honors Schulz with Sparky Award, February 14, 1998 (Box MLM 29)
    - Fry Art Museum, Children of the Yellow Kid, Undated (Box MLM 29)
    - Ohio State University, Festival of Cartoon Art, Undated (Box MLM 29)
    - I went MAD at Artspace magnet, November 6 - December 6, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Press Democrat, Having the time of his life, July 12, 1998 (Box MLM 29)
    - Humor in a Jugular Vein, October 9, 1998 (Box MLM 29)
    - Stamford Museum & Nature Center, Cartooning & Gag Writing Symposium, 1994 (Box MLM 29)
    - Press Democrat, MAD, February 23, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Evansville Museum of Arts and Science, "It's a MAD, MAD, MAD, MAD, World", September/October 1994 (Box MLM 29)
    - Ohio State University, The Face Behind the Laugh, 1995 (Box MLM 29)
    - Seattle Post-Intelligencer, "Stark Raving MAD", August 7, 1993 (Box MLM 29)
    - Press Democrat, "Eight Prominent Cartoonists To Appear in Person at Museum", May 8, 1988 (Box MLM 29)
    - Seattle Times, "What-Me Worry? Dept.", August 6, 1993 (Box MLM 29)
    - Press Democrat, "A MAD, MAD, world", February 23, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Press Democrat, "1,000 fans pack autograph session", February 23, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Seattle Post-Intelligencer, "Stark Raving MAD", August 7, 1993 (Box MLM 29)
    - Press Democrat, "Art 'Toons", February 26, 1995 (Box MLM 29)
    - Journal and Courier, "Neuman and Newman", January 13, 1995 (Box MLM 29)
    - Orion Entertainment, "Third Floor Gallery gets MAD", February 2, 1993 (Box MLM 29)
    - Cartoon Times, "We're MAD About the Next Exhibit!", December 1990 (Box MLM 29)
    - Humor in a Jugular Vein, 1991 (Box MLM 29)
    - Triangle City Magazine, "Remembrance of Things Ecch!", Undated (Box MLM 29)
    - Venture, "Humor in a Jugular Vein", December 31, 1992 - January 6, 1993 (Box MLM 29)
    - Newmark & Lewis, "It's Still MAD", December 17, 1991 (Box MLM 29)
    - New York Newsday, Special Part II Edition MAD "What, Me Forty?", December 17, 1991 (Box MLM 29)
    - Metro Times, "The Legacy of Alfred E. Neuman", April 8-14, 1992 (Box MLM 29)
    - Up the Academy Film Reviews, June 1980 (Box MLM 30, Folder 1)
    - 300th Issue/40th Anniversary, 1990-1992 (Box MLM 30, Folder 2)
    - 35th Anniversary Articles, 1987-1988 (Box MLM 30, Folder 3)
    - 25th Anniversary Articles, 1977 (Box MLM 30, Folder 4)
    - The MAD Show Reviews, 1966 (Box MLM 30, Folder 5)
    - Tales from the Crypt TV, 1990-1994 (Box MLM 30, Folder 6)
    - Spy vs Spy, 1989-1993 (Box MLM 30, Folder 7)
    - Russ Cochran/MAD Art Information, 1986-1992 (Box MLM 30, Folder 8)
    - Obituaries, 1980-1992 (Box MLM 30, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous MAD Mentions, 1960-1994 (Box MLM 30, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1977-1995 (Box MLM 30, Folder 11)
    - Mark Cohen/MAD Art Information [1 of 2], 1992-1994 (Box MLM 30, Folder 12)
    - Mark Cohen/MAD Art Information [2 of 2], 1992-1994 (Box MLM 31, Folder 1)
    - MAD TV, 1995-1996 (Box MLM 31, Folder 2)
    - MAD Merchandise Related, 1989-1994 (Box MLM 31, Folder 3)
    - MAD/EC Inspired Articles, 1967-1991 (Box MLM 31, Folder 4)
    - MAD Gets Bought/DC Articles, 1961-1992 (Box MLM 31, Folder 5)
    - MAD Artist Information, 1982-1996 (Box MLM 31, Folder 6)
    - MAD Art Auctions [1 of 2], 1992-1995 (Box MLM 32, Folder 1)
    - Mad Art Auctions [2 of 2], 1988-1991 (Box MLM 32, Folder 2)
    - Lime Rock/MAD Cards, 1992-1994 (Box MLM 32, Folder 3)
    - General Comic Information, 1988-1993 (Box MLM 32, Folder 4)
    - General Articles About MAD, 1978-1995 (Box MLM 32, Folder 5)
    - Gaines Interviews, 1960-1989 (Box MLM 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign MAD Miscellaneous, 1977-1995 (Box MLM 33, Folder 2)
    - Editorials and Cartoons, 1967-1996 (Box MLM 33, Folder 3)
    - Doll Information, 1986 (Box MLM 33, Folder 4)
    - Cover Spoofs, 1989-1992 (Box MLM 33, Folder 5)
    - Conventions with MAD Featured, 1992-1993 (Box MLM 33, Folder 6)
    - Congressional/I. Berlin Articles, 1954-1994 (Box MLM 33, Folder 7)
    - Completely MAD, 1991-1992 (Box MLM 33, Folder 8)
    - Collectibly MAD, 1995 (Box MLM 33, Folder 9)
  - Articles in Publications, 1951-2000
    - Amateur Radio, April 1967 (Box MLM 4, Item 1)
    - American Cinematogher, June 1980 (Box MLM 4, Item 2)
    - American Cinematogher, December 1987 (Box MLM 4, Item 3)
    - Antique Trader (Weekly) "Mad About MAD", October 20, 1993 (Box MLM 24, Item 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Article about collecting MAD.
    - Antique Week, "These Collections Don't Get Even, They Get MAD", July 16, 1990 (Box MLM 4, Item 4)
      Article about MAD Collecting
    - Aspiring Cartoonist, "An Interview with Sergio Aragones", January 1, 1995 (Box MLM 4, Item 5)
    - Aspiring Cartoonist, "Loose Lines, Neat Feet, and Diggin' Don Knotts", July 1, 1995 (Box MLM 4, Item 6)
      Interview with Jack Davis with illustrations
    - Atlantic Monthly, "The Case for MAD", September 1963 (Box MLM 4, Item 7)
      An essay praising MAD
    - Audacity, Vol. 3, No. 2, Winter, January 1995 (Box MLM 4, Item 8)
      Page 10: adverstisement featuring Jack Davis, MAD references, and Alfred E. Newman cameos
    - Avenues, "Ka-Boom", June 1996 (Box MLM 4, Item 9)
      Article about Baby Boomers with photos of various 1950s-1960s toys and collectibles including MAD Magazine
    - Baby Boomer Collectibles, "A Brave MAD World", December 1993 (Box MLM 4, Item 10)
      Michael Lerner article which explores the history of the MAD universe including a checklist for collectors and a look at of the rarest MAD memorabilia
    - Baby Boomer Collectibles, "EC Comics", March 1994 (Box MLM 4, Item 11)
      Article about the history of EC Comics
    - Baby Boomer Collectibles, February 1995 (Box MLM 4, Item 12)
      A brief review (description) of D. DeBartolo book
    - Baby Boomer Collectibles, "Join us as a subscriber at the special rate", Undated (Box MLM 4, Item 13)
      Subscription flyer with images of MAD Magazines, MAD Collectibles, and Alfred E. Newman
    - Bikini, May 1998 (Box MLM 24, Item 2)
      Al Jaffee illustration.
    - Card Collector Price Guide, "Card Collectors get MAD", July 1993 (Box MLM 4, Item 14)
      Alfred E. Newman on cover; article of Lime Rock/ American Mint MAD card series with photos
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "MAD Magazine's Sergio Aragones, August 1970 (Box MLM 4, Item 15)
      Sergio Aragones cover, The 'MAD' Office, plus article about Aragones
    - Cartoonist Profiles, "Trip to Russia", March 1972 (Box MLM 4, Item 16)
      Article with photos of the 1972 MAD trip to Russia